Hello friends, have you bought a new car or need to
renew your old car's insurance? The
question arises, which car
insurance company is the best? There
are 25 companies offering car insurance in India.
Now, selecting from them becomes a
difficult question. So, I am Mahesh from
Truck Book India. After 30 years of working in R&D,
I give you good
recommendations based on the database, not on hearsay.
I do
n't make any recommendations based on hearsay. So, let's go and
study the database a little bit and
I will explain it to you in an easy way. There is a
report like this from the
Insurance Regulatory Development Authority
of India of IRDAI, which is the official responsible for
publishing this report. The
income
claim settlement ratio of all the insurance companies is shown in their report,
which looks like this. So,
what we will do is just showing you.
Now, this is a snapshot of all the reports. It is on
my website. You can
go there, there is a link in the description of the video, and later you can easily zoom in on this image.
If you are interested, then fine.
So let's first understand what the Income Claim
Ratio (ICR) is, as defined by IRDAI, and what the
companies call the Claim Settlement Ratio (CSRR).
What are these two ratios, and which one
is important for us to select?
First, let's understand the Income Claim Ratio. For
example, a company has collected ₹1 lakh in
premiums from all the people
in a year. The people who have claimed
for car damage, the
money they have given to the people is 80,000. So,
80,000 divided by ₹1 lakh, this ratio is the
ICR. In this case, the ICR is 80.
Okay, so they have returned the money at 80%. The remaining
20%
goes into the company's operational or profit. Okay,
now if this ICR is around 50,
at 50, then there's definitely something fishy about it.
What does it mean? The company is taking ₹1
from the people but only giving back 50%.  So
this means that your chances of getting a claim settlement
reduce. And if the
ICR of a company is above 100, it means that the
company is taking ₹1 and giving more,
so it means that it is making a loss. Of course, it does
not matter for itself, but as per the
financial stability of the company, it is
not equal. Now, the second is the claim settlement
ratio which companies give on their website.
What is this? If a company receives
100 claims for car damage and the company
gives money to suppose 99 people and approves the claims, then 99
divided by 100 is the
claim settlement
ratio. So, the higher it is, the better it will be.
If it is 100, it means that if 100
claims come, then
they give money to all 100 people. Now, this
seems a little difficult practically. Of course, there is
a company which provides 100% claim
settlement.  The ratio is maintained in India.
So let's see, the same chart that I
showed earlier of IRDA, plus
more data lake, I have created this chart.
Now this is the second column, it shows the name of the insurer. The
third column is showing the claim settlement
ratio, which is important for us.
So, above the one which is visible in green color,
I have sorted all these 25 companies.
Okay, so the one which has the best
claim settlement ratio is at
number one in the top, after that it is at number two,
after that it is at number three. You will see that
SBI is at the top with 100% claim
settlement ratio. After that comes
99.1, after that comes
HDFC.com. This ratio is
not important for us, it shows the financial stability of the company.
Now if you
look at it, I have highlighted some places in red color.
Okay, all these companies are a little
below and some of them are
government companies, so you can see that
their ICR is above 100.  It means
they are taking ₹1 from the customer as a
premium and are giving back more than that amount,
so it means the
company is making a loss. Of course, it does not even come in the top 10,
so we will not talk about it. The
column next to it is
important. Why are network garages
important for me? Right now I keep travelling.
Suppose I go to Kerala and
my car gets damaged and
I call the company whose insurance I have taken.
If their network
garage is nearby, then what will happen?
They will immediately tow my car and take it away. It will be a
cashless transfer mostly. So, after doing the
complete repair, they will give me back the
car and the money will be
settled directly between the company and the garage. So, for this, the
more network garages there are, the
better it is for us.
For this, I have given it in the last column.
This font is a little small, so let us go to the
next page in which I am
showing only the top 10 companies.
Look, right now the chart is a little bigger, it looks good. The
first one is our SBI.  There is 100% claim
settlement ratio, the second one is Ko
99.1, ADAC Rago
99, Tata AIG 99, Royal Serum 98.6, the remaining
five companies all have
claim settlement ratio above 98. Now let's come to
our point that all these top 10 companies are good for us, out of these,
whose network garages are the best, SBI has the highest,
brother, they have 16000 plus network garages,
now whenever I try this for myself or
my friends, I see that the
insurance premium of Ko is the
lowest, but if you see,
their network garages, I have
written N because they do not give the list
of network garages on their official website,
I called their
helpline, what did they say, whenever your
car gets damaged, you should call us, there
is a garage nearby, you will be immediately
allocated, your car will be towed there and
we will repair it, so don't
worry, if I have a little doubt,
I have written a little  You did this research
for any company that you want to finalize, keep in
mind that the lowest quotation you get is for
Ko. Now I went through different
websites. I think the best website is
Team BHP because it is a
small brand. The customers here are
standard and give very realistic feedback. So let's go
there and I will show you
how to research a couple of companies. Okay, so here we are,
we have reached the Team BHP
website. Okay, where people are
talking about Ko.
I have already done some study,
so I will skip a bit. Wherever people have
said anything, it is relevant too. For quite some
time, okay, in many places, see here he is saying
that I have a fairly good experience
with Ko. You can read the story later.
What is the full story? Here the guy is saying that
I have a great experience with Ko.
Okay, this is a review from 2023. I had a
good claim experience with Ko for my other
car
total.  There was a loss of a car,
he had worked with Coco, let me first show you the car,
see how much damage it has done, see this, see
this is the condition of his car, as
I said, I have given the link
in the description of the video, after this guy's car became like this, a
police case was filed to settle the entire claim of the car,
after doing all this you can see,
overall it took three months from the date of the
accident to the date of final payment, I was
happy with Eko at the end, okay,
even after such huge damage, the guy has
said this, so according to me, in this way
you should research any company, what
people are saying about their claim settlement is
more important,
what the company is saying is also important,
but what people are saying is more important than what people are saying
because we are the public, if
we like the company then that company is good
and we have seen anyway, we selected the top 10
companies whose claim
settlement ratio is already above 9%  Okay, so let's go
back to the chart and see
how we did the research on Team BHP,
so in this way
you can research any company and these 10 out of 10
companies are the best, out of them
you can go with the company which gives you the lowest premium, according to me, so I hope this
is helpful to you in your car
insurance, thank you so much,
I keep making videos on many such subjects, keep
suggesting and subscribe.